Amazon Buy Shipping is a tool available to sellers
who handle fulfillment of their own products.
This is called Fulfilled by Merchant or FBM.
When you receive an order and prepare to ship it
to your customer, you have a few options.
You can ship your order with a carrier of your choice
and confirm that the product is on its way
to your customer by providing a tracking ID,
or you can use Amazon Buy Shipping.
Amazon Buy Shipping lets you purchase
and print shipping labels
and automatically confirms and tracks shipping
in Seller Central, as well as some third-party tools.
Amazon takes care of your shipping details
and provides recommendations for shipping services
in our network of trusted carriers
that are highly likely to deliver on time,
fit your preferences, and offer the lowest available cost.
This can help you provide your customers
with the fast, reliable shipping they love.
Amazon Buy Shipping also helps safeguard
your performance metrics, which impact your account health.
Good account health is essential
to remaining an active seller in the Amazon store.
When selecting your carrier with Amazon Buy Shipping,
you'll see the option to purchase shipping labels
marked as OTDR protected.
OTDR, or on-time delivery rate,
measures how often your products are delivered
by the promised delivery date you set.
By using a shipping label that is OTDR protected,
your on-time delivery rate will not be impacted
even if your shipment arrives late.
Note that you will need to have shipping settings automation
and automated handling time on the shipping settings page
enabled to take advantage of OTDR protected labels.
Learn more about these tools
by searching Shipping Settings Automation
and Automated Handling Time in Seller Central.
Amazon Buy Shipping can also protect you
against A to Z guarantee claims related to delivery issues.
We will cover the cost of these claims
and stop them from impacting your OTDR
if you purchased a shipping label marked as claims protected.
Making sure all your shipments have valid tracking numbers
is another important step that Amazon Buy Shipping helps
support.
We automatically upload tracking information
for all orders that use Amazon Buy Shipping,
which helps you maintain your valid tracking rate or VTR
and makes it easy for you and your customer
to see where an order is in the delivery process.
To learn how to use Amazon Buy Shipping for your next order,
search using Amazon Buy Shipping for seller-fulfilled orders
on Seller Central.